Volume is such a key component to growth
on social
media.
And I'm not talking about social media,
I'm not talking about your
followers,
I'm not talking about subscribers.
I'm talking about you.
The growth is you, how you speak,
how you present yourself, your pacing,
your
cadence, how you edit,
even becoming comfortable talking to
camera.
I would much rather you did
that 30 times a month than four, because
if on a Monday you put a half an hour into
a piece of content and it bombs, on
Tuesday you can start fresh.
If you put a week into creating a video
and it
bombs, that's a week of low confidence,
potentially low mood, low
motivation. And for me,
I'm a very impulsive person.
Ed, in his video,
talks about how he strategizes
and plans and whatever.
I watched his video on the way back from
Sydney just now.
I drove past my house to the studio to
film this video after the flight with no
planning, no strategy.
I have a rough idea of my thumbnail,
and I think an analogy
that sums this up really well would be
what Alex Hormozi said on Chris's podcast,
and I'll show you the clip here.
Have you heard the story of the pottery
class?
There's a teacher,
and he's got two classes that he teaches.
And one class he says,
"The only assignment for this whole
semester is that you
come back with the perfect clay pot.
That's it.
That's the assignment." The other class he
says, "Your objective is to make the
most total quantity of clay pots,
and you'll be measured by how many pots
you
make." And at the end of the quarter,
the pots that came from the team that
had to just make sheer volume,
not only did they make more pots,
but the quality of
all of their pots
was better compared to the teams
that only had to make one.
And it just underlines the biggest lesson
that I've learned in my life, which is
that volume negates luck.
You can try to be lucky
and pick the one perfect
thing and try and make it, but
if you don't want to try and be lucky,
you can just
do so much fucking work
that you will brute force your way to
figuring it out.
Instead of seeing it as YouTube versus
short-form content, let's look at both of
these as tools to utilize
when developing a personal brand.
If you are putting more than 45 minutes
into a reel, I think you're putting too
much effort into it for a start.
But rather than looking at this as
something that
just gets you clients,
let's look at short-form content as
something that gets you
reps